C.E. Britten Cattle Company papers, 1943-1958
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
C.E. Britten Cattle Company papers, 1943-1958
MS 429
C.E. Britten, 1893-1970.
Papers (1943-1958). This collection contains the papers of the C.E. Britten Cattle Company. Britten worked for thirty-two years as a bonded livestock dealer; he was a cattle ranch manager and owner between the Sasabe and Three Points, Arizona area. Materials in the collection are C.E. Britten's business files including: livestock auction sheets, bill of sale drafts, contracts, order books, and weight sheets. All materials are in English.
2.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Clarence E. Britten (1893-1970) was a cattle ranch manager and owner in the area between Sasabe and Three Points, Arizona; he worked for thirty-two years as a bonded livestock dealer. Britten was born in California and worked for his father's freighting and guide business before moving to Arizona in 1926 to work as foreman of a ranch near Sasabe, Arizona. Beginning in 1932, he worked for the Arizona Highway Patrol for three and a half years. Afterwards, Britten managed various cattle ranches until 1950 when he bought his own ranch near the Sasabe and Three Points area. Over the years Britten was active in various community organizations: he was the captain of the Pima County Sherriff's Posse in 1951, the grand marshal of the rodeo parade in 1963, a Republican precinct committeeman, and a member of the Old Pueblo Club, the Ancient and Accepted Scottish Rite of Freemasonry, the Cattle Grower's Association, the Mountain Oyster's Club Board of Directors, and the Tucson Rodeo Parade Planning Committee. He died at the age of 77 in 1970.
Organization
This Collection is organized into 1 series:
Series I: Business Files, 1943-1958
Scope and Content Note
Papers (1943-1958). This collection contains the business files of the C.E. Britten Cattle Company. Clarence E. Britten (1893-1970) worked for thirty-two years as a bonded livestock dealer; he was a cattle ranch manager and owner between the Sasabe and Three Points, Arizona, area. Materials in the collection include livestock auction sheets (1954-1955), bill of sale drafts (1955-1958), contracts (1944-1958), order books (1943-1950), and weight sheets (1950-1958). Also included are a few business materials from two other cattle companies: Avent Brothers and Vail and Vickers. All materials are in English.
Access Terms
Britten, Clarence Ernest, 1893-1970.
Cattle trade--Arizona--Pima County.
Container List
- Series 1: Business Files 1943-1958
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains auction sheets (1954-1955), bill of sale drafts (1955-1958), contracts (1944-1958), order books (1943-1950), and weight sheets (1950-1958). Also included is an undated notebook along with two other cattle companies' materials including Avent Brothers Weight Sheets (1954) and a Vail and Vickers Receipt Book (1957-1958). All materials are in English.
  - Auction Sheets. 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bill of Sale Drafts. 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bill of Sale Drafts. 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Contracts. 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Contracts. 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Contracts. 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Contracts. 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General - Avent Brothers Weight Sheets. 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General - Notes. undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General - Vail and Vickers Receipt Book. 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Order Books. 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Order Books. 1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Order Books. 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Order Books. 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Order Books. 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Order Books. 1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Order Books. 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Order Books. 1949 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Order Books (folder 1 of 2). 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Order Books (folder 2 of 2). 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Weight Sheets. 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Weight Sheets. 1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Weight Sheets. 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Weight Sheets. 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Weight Sheets. 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Weight Sheets. 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Weight Sheets. 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Weight Sheets. 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)